airahyusuff.netlify.app

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Email | airahyusuff@gmail.com Mobile | +234 703 855 3898

ABOUT ME

I'm a Frontend Engineer with 3+ years of experience developing visually appealing web applications with delightful user experience. As an avid learner, I thrive in work environments that provide measurable metrics for career growth, great opportunities for skills improvement and promotes close team collaborations and soft skills acquisition.

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 - Present | Frontend Engineer - Cova Inc.

- Collaborate in teams to continuously build, optimise and improve the Cova web app.
- Crafted technical documentation for existing projects in the codebase to improve onboarding processes for new members on the frontend team.

July 2020 - August 2021 | Frontend Developer - SWIPE Limited

- Collaborated in teams to build digital products with optimised user experience using JavaScript and CSS-in-JS tools.
- Optimised existing codebase of a payment web app and built 4 new functionalities within 1 month of working with React and Redux.
- Crafted and delivered detailed feedback reports to improve work efficiency and communication within teams.

June 2019 - May 2020 | Web Developer - Mental Care Foundation

- Designed and developed the organization's main website.
- Established a 50% increase in volunteers and members participation by building an emotional support web app with live chat functionality for both users.

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019 | Developer Intern - Crenet TechLabs

- Eliminated errors for 3 client projects by testing product features.
- Minimized execution downtime for 3 projects by restructuring the UIs with design templates.
- Published 2 articles with social media promotion, leading to a substantial increase in company visibility.

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018 | **Software Engineering Intern -** Terragon Group

- Collaborated with a team to create a sample design of a hostel finder application.
- Built a website that featured book recommendations.
- · Designed and developed a blog with basic blog features like creating, editing and deleting posts.

SKILLS

React, Gatsby, Vue, Nuxt, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, CSS-in-JS, GraphQL, VCS, CI/CD

EDUCATION

Feb 2020 | B.Sc (Honours) Computer Engineering - Obafemi Awolowo University

- Best Graduating Student, Department of Computer Science and Engineering
- 4.77/5.0 CGPA

Nov 2021 | Programming for Data Science with Python Nanodegree - Udacity

PROJECTS

Mar 2022 - Callerview Admin - Admin dashboard for Callerview. https://callerview.netlify.app

Dec 2021 - FilterPay - A webpage that tracks user payments and activities. https://filter-pay.netlify.app

Mar 2021 - **Teume Project -** A KPOP group fan website. https://treasureproject.netlify.app/

May 2020 - MCF - An non-profit organisation website. https://formermcf.netlify.app/

Feb 2020 - **AutiMS -** A therapy reports app and progress tracker (PWA). https://autims.netlify.app/

May 2019 - **KhayY -** A web-based online shopping platform. https://shop.khairahscorner.com/

Jan 2019 - **MePaint -** A website that allows users to pick colors and get decor inspo. https://mepaint.netlify.app/